Finding Aid for George Romney Papers 1920s-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Governor's Papers
  - Chronological
    - 1965
      - General Subjects
        - Articles for Publication (Box 116)
        - Atomic Energy (Box 116)
        - John Birch Society (Box 116)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 116)
        - Cancer Research (Box 116)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 116)
        - Celebrations (Box 116)
        - Certificates, citations (Box 116)
        - Civil Rights
          - General [A-Z] (Box 116)
          - Selma sympathy march [A-L] (Box 116)
          - Selma sympathy march [M-Z] (Box 419)
          - Selma sympathy march (critical of GR) (Box 419)
          - Liuzzo slaying (Box 419)
          - Railbach, Michael (Box 419)
        - Code of Fair Practices (Box 419)
        - Communism (Box 419)
        - Community Chest (Box 419)
        - Conferences (Box 419)
        - Constitution (Box 419)
        - Con-Con 1963 (including examples of deceptive literature) (Box 419)
        - Consulates (Box 117)
        - Council of State Government (Box 117)
        - Counties [arranged alphabetically] (Box 117)
        - Countries
          - African (Box 117)
          - Mexico (Box 117)
        - Courts (Box 117)
        - Detroit
          - General (Box 117)
          - Azzam Problem (Box 117)
          - Metropolitan Regional Planning Commission (Box 117)
        - Disaster Relief
          - Tornado Relief (Box 117)
          - Livestock Feed (Box 117)
        - Divorce (Box 117)
        - Drams; Sewers (Box 117)
        - Economic Opportunity (Box 117)
        - Education
          - Background Material (Box 117)
          - School Re-organization (Box 117)
          - Special Education (Box 117)
          - Dearborn School District Experiment (Box 117)
          - Detroit School Finance 1963-1964 (Box 117)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 118)
        - Elections
          - General (Box 118)
          - Voting Age (Box 118)
        - Employment (Box 118)
        - Executive Office (Box 118)
        - Executive Orders (Box 118)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 118)
        - Gambling (Box 118)
        - Governors Conferences 1963-1966
          - Minneapolis July 1965 (Box 118)
          - Los Angeles July 1966 (Box 118)
          - Cleveland June 1964 (Box 118)
          - Miami July 1963 (Box 118)
        - Governors Mansion (Box 118)
        - Greater Michigan Foundation, 2 folders (Box 118)
        - Hope (Box 118)
        - Human Resources Council (Box 118)
        - Housing
          - General (Box 119)
          - West Central Organization Material (Box 119)
        - Immigration (Box 119)
        - Inter-Agency Council for Recreation (Box 119)
        - Interview concerning Citizens Day (Box 119)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 119)
        - Introductions (Box 119)
        - Invitations (outgoing) (Box 119)
        - Judgeships (Box 119)
        - Labor (General) (Box 119)
        - Legal Problems (sampled)
          - [A-C, H-K, N, P, R-S, U] (Box 119)
        - Legislative Salaries [A-Z] (Box 120)
        - Legislature, Members of
          - General (Box 120)
          - Peggy Allen (gambling) (Box 120)
        - Lobbyists (Box 120)
        - Local Government (Box 120)
        - Messages of the Governor (Box 120)
        - Messages of Greeting [A-Z] (Box 120)
        - Moral Rearmament (Box 120)
        - Music (Box 120)
        - Newspapers (Box 120)
        - Olympics (Box 120)
        - Ordinances (Box 120)
        - Organizations (Box 120)
        - People to People (Box 121)
        - Political Job (Box 121)
        - Political
          - General [A-Z] (Box 121)
        - Press Releases (Box 121)
        - Radio - TV (Box 121)
        - Recommendations (Box 121)
        - Red Cross (Box 121)
        - Removals
          - General (Box 121)
          - Chesterfield Township Board (Box 121)
        - Reorganization of State Government (Box 121)
        - Resolutions (Box 121)
        - Roads (Box 121)
        - Safety (general) (Box 121)
        - Savings Bonds (Box 121)
        - Sex Deviates (Box 121)
        - Sponsor (Box 121)
        - Statements for Publication (Box 121)
        - States [arranged alphabetically by name of state] (Box 121)
        - Subscriptions (Box 121)
        - Taxation (Box 122)
          - A-Z (Box 122)
          - Aged (Box 122)
          - Beer Tax (Box 122)
          - Income Tax (Box 122)
          - Intangible Tax (Box 122)
        - Transportation (Box 122)
        - Unemployment (Box 122)
        - Unions (Box 122)
        - United Nations (Box 122)
        - Vacancy
          - Judges (Box 122)
          - Legislature (Box 122)
        - Veterans Day (Box 123)
        - Vietnam: Operation Christmas in Vietnam, 10 folders (Box 123)
        - Weather (Box 123)
        - Wolverine Boys State (Box 123)
        - World's Fair (Box 123)
        - Young American Medals (Box 124)
        - Youth Commission
          - Sam Rabinowitz file (Box 124)
          - General (Box 124)
        - Youth Conference (Box 124)
        - Youth Program file (Box 124)
        - Youth Employment 1963-1964 (Box 124)
        - Youth Commission Blueprint (Box 124)
        - Youth for Understanding 1964 (Box 124)
        - Miscellaneous
          - A-D (Box 124)
          - E-M (Box 125)
          - N-Z (Box 126)
      - Legislative Files
        - Miscellaneous [A-R] (Box 127)
        - Miscellaneous [S-Z] (Box 128)
        - Future Legislation (Box 128)
        - Tax Exemption (H.B. 2001) (Box 128)
        - Sunday Liquor Sales (H.B. 2149) (Box 128)
        - Registration (H.B. 2159) (Box 128)
        - Upper Peninsula Mineral Rights (S.B. 531) (Box 128)
        - Drivers Age (Box 128)
        - Uninsured Motorist (Box 128)
        - Workmen's Compensation (S.B. 114) (Box 128)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous [A-Z] (Box 129)
        - Peace Corps (Box 129)
        - Physical Fitness (Box 129)
        - Prayer in Schools (Box 129)
        - Vietnam, 3 folders (Box 129)
        - U.S. Congress (Box 129)
        - U.S. Senate (Box 129)
        - Cabinet
          - Agriculture Department (Box 129)
          - Air (Box 129)
          - Army (Box 129)
          - Attorney General (Box 129)
          - Commerce (Box 129)
          - Defense (Box 129)
          - Health, Education and Welfare
            - General (Box 129)
            - Social Security (Box 129)
          - Interior (Box 129)
          - Labor (Box 129)
          - Navy (Box 129)
          - Postmaster General (Box 130)
          - Secretary of State (Box 130)
          - Treasury (Box 130)
        - Executive Branch
          - Civil Service Commission (Box 130)
          - Communications (Box 130)
          - Housing (Box 130)
          - Intergovernmental Relations (Box 130)
          - Internal Revenue (Box 130)
          - Interstate Commerce (Box 130)
          - Power Commission (Box 130)
          - Small Business Administration (Box 130)
          - Trade Commission (Box 130)
        - Legislation
          - Miscellaneous (Box 130)
          - Higher Education (H.R. 9567) (Box 130)
          - Medical Care for the Aged (Box 130)
          - Sleeping Bear (Box 130)
      - Military Affairs
        - Civil Defense
          - General (Box 130)
        - Adjutant General
          - Schnipke file (Box 130)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 130)
        - Military Board (Box 130)
        - Military Study Commission (Box 130)
        - Naval Board (Box 130)
        - National Guard
          - Schnipke file (Box 130)
          - Reorganization (Box 130)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 131)
        - Selective Service (Box 131)
        - Veterans Trust Fund
          - L. LaLone file (Box 131)
          - General (Box 131)
        - Veterans
          - General (Box 131)
          - Homestead Tax Exemption (Box 131)
    - 1966
      - Boards and Commissions
        - Budget Department
          - Glenn S. Allen file (Box 131)
          - Establishment of Budget Department in Executive Office (Box 131)
          - General (Box 131)
          - Building Commission (Box 131)
        - Administration, Department of (Box 132)
          - Administrative Board (General) (Box 132)
          - Administrative Board Meetings (folders for each bi-weekly meeting, January-November 15) (Box 132)
          - Administrative Board Meetings (folders for each bi-weekly meeting, December 6-20) (Box 133)
          - G. Washington, Director (Box 133)
          - Establishment of the Department of Administration (Box 133)
          - Data Processing (Box 133)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 133)
          - Council for the Arts (Box 133)
          - Retirement Boards
            - Judges Retirement (Box 133)
            - Probate Judges (Box 133)
            - Legislative Retirement System (Box 133)
            - Municipal Employees (Box 133)
            - Public School Employees (Box 133)
            - State Employees (Box 133)
          - Veteran's Trust Fund (Box 133)
        - Agriculture, Department of
          - B. Dale Ball file (Box 133)
          - Executive Order Establishing Department of Agriculture (Box 133)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 133)
          - Milk (Box 133)
          - Insecticides (Box 133)
          - Apple Commission (Box 133)
          - Cherry Commission (Box 133)
          - Fair Authority (Box 133)
          - Upper Peninsula Fair Authority (Box 133)
          - Potato Commission (Box 133)
          - Racing Commission
            - Berry Beaman file (Box 133)
            - General (Box 133)
            - Fenton [A-B] (Box 133)
            - Fenton [C-Z] (Box 134)
            - Gambling and racing letters [A-F] (Box 134)
            - Gambling and racing letters [G-Z] (Box 135)
          - Soil Conservation (Box 135)
        - Attorney General
          - Frank Kelley file (Box 135)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 135)
          - Petitions (various states) (Box 135)
          - Opinions (Box 135)
          - Studded Tires (Box 135)
        - Auditor General (Box 135)
        - Civil Rights, Department of
          - Burton I. Gordin file (Box 135)
          - Establishing Department (Box 135)
          - Age Discrimination (Box 135)
          - General [A-L] (Box 135)
          - General [M-Z] (Box 136)
          - Housing (Box 136)
        - Civil Service, Department of
          - Franklin K. De Wald file (Box 136)
          - Establishing Department (Box 136)
          - Driver Improvement Program for State Employees (Box 136)
          - Welfare Department (Box 136)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 136)
        - Civil War Centennial (Box 136)
        - Commerce, Department of
          - Robert McIntosh file (Box 136)
          - Creating Department of Commerce (Box 136)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 136)
          - Upper Great Lake Regional Economic Development Commission (Box 136)
          - Aeronautics Board (Box 136)
          - Banking (Box 136)
          - Economic Expansion
            - B.M. Conboy file (Box 136)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 136)
            - Copper Hill Ski (Box 137)
            - World Trade Advisory Council (Box 137)
          - Insurance Department
            - Wickstrom File (Box 137)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 137)
          - Liquor Control Commission
            - Don Leonard file (Box 137)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 137)
          - Public Service Commission
            - Peter Spivak file (Box 137)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 138)
        - Conservation, Department of
          - Ralph A. MacMullen file (Box 138)
          - Establishment of Department (Box 138)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 138)
          - Deer [A-F] (Box 138)
          - Deer [G-Z] (Box 139)
          - Interstate Oil Compact Commission (Box 139)
          - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 139)
          - Tourist Council (Box 139)
          - Water Resources Commission
            - Loring Oeming file (Box 139)
            - Grand River (Box 139)
            - Water Levels (Box 139)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 139)
          - Waterways Commission
            - Keith Wilson file (Box 139)
            - General (Box 139)
        - Corrections, Department of
          - Gus Harrison file (Box 139)
          - Establishment of Department of Corrections (Box 139)
          - Pardons and Paroles (General) (Box 139)
          - Pardons and Commutations case records [A-Z] (Box 140)
        - Education, Department of
          - Alexander J. Kloster file (Box 140)
          - Establishment of Department of Education (Box 140)
          - Amish (Box 140)
          - School for the Blind (Box 140)
          - School for the Deaf (Box 140)
          - Michigan Rehabilitation Institute (Box 140)
          - General [A-L] (Box 140)
          - General [M-Z] (Box 141)
          - Colleges
            - Miscellaneous (Box 141)
            - Communism (Box 141)
            - Communist Speaker at State Universities (Box 141)
            - Central Michigan University (Box 141)
            - Eastern Michigan University (Box 141)
            - Ferris State College (Box 141)
            - Grand Valley State College (Box 141)
            - Michigan State University
              - General (Box 141)
              - Cherry Industry (Box 141)
              - Printing Shops (Box 141)
              - Oakland (Box 141)
            - Michigan Technological University (Box 141)
            - Northern Michigan University (Box 141)
            - Saginaw Valley College (Box 141)
            - University of Michigan (Box 141)
            - Wayne State University (Box 141)
            - Western Michigan University (Box 141)
        - Education, State Board of
          - Higher Education Assistance Authority (Box 142)
          - Higher Education Facilities Commission (Box 142)
          - New Lothrop School District (Box 142)
          - Department of Education Library Board (Box 142)
          - Department of Vocational Rehabilitation [A-Z] (Box 142)
        - Great Lakes Commission (Box 142)
        - Highway Department
          - Howard E. Hill file (Box 142)
          - Establishment of Highway Department (Box 142)
          - Beautification and Landscaping (Box 142)
          - Dangerous Areas (Box 142)
          - General [A-F] (Box 142)
          - General [G-Z] (Box 143)
          - Housing for Families Displaced by Highway Construction (Box 143)
          - I-696 [A-Z] (Box 143)
          - Romeo (Box 143)
          - Telegraph Road (Box 144)
          - Trees (Box 144)
          - International Bridge (Box 144)
          - Mackinac Bridge (Box 144)
        - Labor, Department of
          - Thomas Roumell file (Box 144)
          - Reorganization (Box 144)
          - Establishment of Department of Labor (Box 144)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 144)
          - Construction Safety Commission (Box 144)
          - Employment Security Commission
            - M. Lovell file (Box 144)
            - General (Box 144)
            - Irregularities (Box 144)
            - Manpower Training (Box 144)
            - General [A-F] (Box 144)
            - General [G-Z] (Box 145)
            - Appeal Board (Box 145)
          - Labor Mediation Board
            - General (Box 145)
            - Benton Harbor School Teachers (Box 145)
            - Racing (Box 145)
            - Teachers Strike (Box 145)
          - Workmen's Compensation Board
            - General [A-Z] (Box 145)
            - Agricultural Workers [A-Z] (Box 145)
            - Appeal Board (Box 145)
        - Licensing and Regulation, Department of
          - L. G. Sculthorp file (Box 146)
          - Establishment of Department of Licensing and Regulation (Box 146)
          - Accountancy Board (Box 146)
          - Architects Board (Box 146)
          - Athletic Board of Control (Box 146)
          - Barber Board (Box 146)
          - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 146)
          - Cosmetology Board (Box 146)
          - Dentistry Board (Box 146)
          - Electrical Board (Box 146)
          - Horology Board (Box 146)
          - Law Board (Box 146)
          - Medicine Board (Box 146)
          - Mortuary Board (Box 146)
          - Nursing Board (Box 146)
          - Optometry Board (Box 146)
          - Pharmacy Board (Box 146)
          - Plumbing Board (Box 146)
          - Private Employment Bureau (Box 146)
          - Residential Builders and Maintenance and Alteration Contractors Board (Box 146)
          - Ski Safety Division (Box 146)
          - Water Well Drillers Board (Box 146)
        - Lieutenant Governor (Box 146)
        - Mental Health, Department of
          - Robert A. Kimmick file (Box 146)
          - Establishment of Department of Mental Health (Box 146)
          - Mental Health Facilities Advisory Council (Box 146)
          - Conference on Community Health Programs December 1965 (Box 146)
          - Mental Health Budget, 1966/1967 (Box 146)
          - Governors Conference (Box 146)
          - Mental Retardation Job Placement Program 1964-1966 (Box 146)
          - Caro State Hospital (Box 146)
          - Coldwater State Home and Training School (Box 146)
          - Fort Custer State Home (Box 146)
          - Ionia State Hospital (Box 146)
          - Kalamazoo State Hospital (Box 146)
          - Traverse City State Hospital (Box 146)
          - Ypsilanti State Hospital (Box 146)
          - Lapeer State Home and Training School (Box 147)
          - Mount Pleasant State Hospital (Box 147)
          - Newberry State Hospital (Box 147)
          - Northville State Hospital (Box 147)
          - Pontiac State Hospital (Box 147)
          - Traverse City State Hospital (Box 147)
          - Ypsilanti State Hospital (Box 147)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 147)
        - Military Affairs, Department of
          - Maj. Gen. C.E. Schnipke file (Box 147)
          - Establishment of Department of Military Affairs (Box 147)
          - Military Board (Box 147)
          - Adjutant General (Box 147)
          - National Guard
            - Cecil L. Simmons file (Box 147)
            - General (Box 147)
          - Naval Board (Box 148)
          - Veterans
            - Bonus (Box 148)
            - General (Box 148)
            - Homestead Tax (Box 148)
            - Selective Service (Box 148)
        - Police, Department of State
          - Establishment of Department of State Police (Box 148)
          - Frederick Davids file (Box 148)
          - Civil Defense
            - F. Davids file (Box 148)
            - Michigan Office of Emergency Planning (Box 148)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 148)
          - Accident Reports (Box 148)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 148)
          - Motorcycles (Box 149)
          - State Fire Safety Board (Box 149)
          - Shipman file (Box 149)
          - Traffic Safety Dinner (Box 149)
          - Safety Division - White House Conference June 3, 1966 (Box 149)
          - Michigan Women's Traffic Safety Conference (Box 149)
          - Safety Division Testimony HR 13228 and 13290 (Box 149)
          - Gordon Sheehe file (Box 149)
          - Governor's Letters concerning Safety (Box 149)
          - Safety Commission
            - Gerald W. Shipman file (Box 149)
            - General [A-K] (Box 149)
            - General [L-Z] (Box 150)
            - Monthly Meetings (Box 150)
        - Public Health, Department of
          - Albert R. Heustis File (Box 150)
          - Establishment of Department of Health (Box 150)
          - General [A-F] (Box 150)
          - General [G-Z] (Box 151)
          - Air Pollution (Box 151)
          - Alcoholism Commission (Box 151)
          - Caro Community Hospital (Box 151)
          - Escanaba Laboratory (Box 151)
          - National Enquirer Dogs (Box 151)
          - Crippled Children Commission (Box 151)
          - Veterans Facility (Box 151)
        - Social Services, Department of
          - B. Houston file (Box 151)
          - Establishment of Department of Social Services (Box 151)
          - Boys Training School (Box 151)
          - Girls Training School (Box 151)
          - Family Planning (Box 151)
          - Michigan Industries for the Blind (Box 151)
          - Inter-State Compact on Juveniles (Box 151)
          - Medicare (Box 151)
          - General [A-Z] [sample taken] (Box 152)
          - Aging Commission (Box 152)
          - Indian Affairs (Box 152)
          - State Housing Development Authority (Box 152)
        - State, Department of
          - James Hare file (Box 152)
          - Establishment of Department of State (Box 152)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 153)
          - Historical Commission (Box 153)
        - Supreme Court
          - General (Box 153)
          - Gaylord, City of (Box 153)
        - Treasury, Department of
          - Allison Green file (Box 153)
          - General (Box 153)
          - Escheats Board (Box 153)
          - Revenue Department
            - C. Lock file (Box 153)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 153)
          - Urban Affairs Commission (Box 154)
          - State Tax Commission (Box 154)
      - General Subjects
        - Accomplishments (Box 154)
        - Adoption (Box 154)
        - Advertising (Box 154)
        - American Motors (Box 154)
        - Appointments (Box 154)
        - Apportionment (Box 154)
        - Armed Forces Day (Box 154)
        - Articles for Publication (Box 154)
        - Atomic Energy (Box 154)
        - John Birch Society (Box 154)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 154)
        - Cancer Crusade (Box 154)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 154)
        - Celebrations (Box 154)
        - Certificates, citations (Box 154)
        - Charters
          - General (Box 154)
          - Amendments - Petoskey (Box 154)
        - Communism (Box 154)
        - Community Chest (Box 154)
        - Conferences (Box 154)
        - Con-Con (Box 154)
        - Consulates (Box 154)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 154)
        - County of [arranged alphabetically] (Box 154)
        - Country of
          - India (Box 154)
        - Courts (Box 154)
        - Detroit, City of (Box 154)
        - Disaster Relief
          - General (Box 154)
          - Feed Area (Box 154)
        - Divorce (Box 154)
        - Economic Opportunity, 2 folders (Box 154)
        - Education
          - General [A-Z] (Box 155)
          - Higher Education (Box 155)
          - TV (Box 155)
          - School Drop-Outs (Box 155)
        - Elections (Box 155)
        - Employment (General) (Box 155)
        - Equal Opportunity (Box 155)
        - Executive Office (Box 155)
        - Executive Orders (Box 155)
        - Freedom from Hunger 1964-1966 (Box 155)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 155)
        - Gambling (Box 155)
        - Governors Conference (Box 155)
        - Governors Mansion (Box 155)
        - Grand Jury (Box 155)
        - Greater Michigan Authority (Box 155)
        - HOPE (Box 155)
        - Housing
          - General (Box 155)
          - Urban Redevelopment - West Central Organization (Box 155)
        - Human Resources Council (Box 156)
        - Immigration (Box 156)
        - Inflation (Box 156)
        - Inter-Agency Council for Recreation (Box 156)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 156)
        - Introductions (Box 156)
        - Invitations (outgoing) (Box 156)
        - Invitations (outgoing), concerning dinner, veterans groups (Box 156)
        - Judgeships (Box 156)
        - Labor (General) (Box 156)
        - Legal Holidays (Box 156)
        - Legal Problems [A-Z] [sample taken] (Box 156)
        - Legislature, Members of (Box 157)
        - Letters to Department Heads (Box 157)
        - Lobbyists (Box 157)
        - Local Government
          - General (Box 157)
          - Conferences March 24-May 9, 1966
            - Pontiac (Box 157)
            - Lansing (Box 157)